Gregory Strom

Full Stack Web Developer

Web developer with 11 years of experience creating, maintaining & updating academic websites while employed as a University-level lecturer on philosophy and logic. Seeking to expand my development career by redeploying analytic & communication skills honed through international collaboration with students and colleagues, solving conceptual problems and putting exciting ideas to work.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Movie API | https://github.com/greg-strom/movie api

API built with Node, Express, JS, MongoDB that provides info about movies

Angular client | https://greg-strom.github.io/myFlix-Angular-client/

Front-end client for the movie API built with Angular

React client | https://github.com/greg-strom/myflix-react-client/

Front-end client for the movie API built with React

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Pittsburgh, Department of Physics & Astronomy

Administrative Secretary | September 2019 - present | Pittsburgh

 Created, maintained and updated the "Coffee House" website facilitating international collaboration between chemists and physicists on groundbreaking research publications

University of Pittsburgh, Department of Philosophy

Website Manager, Visiting Lecturer/Instructor | 2011, 2013 – 2021 | Pittsburgh

- Taught myself HTML & CSS to maintain and update faculty supervisor's academic website, augmenting availability of his research to colleagues
- Reinstated and organized annual Visitors' Conference, permanently enriching Department culture by establishing international professional relationships between philosophers in 6 universities
- Enhanced Department's teaching capability by adventurously expanding teaching repertoire to include 9 new subjects, crafting syllabuses and delivering lectures for 27 undergraduate and 17 adult education courses
- Supervised and evaluated teams of 2-4 teaching assistants

Math-M-Addicts

Assistant Teacher | September 2020 – June 2022 | New York

 Used web-based education technology to teach weekly courses on advanced math concepts for children ages 10-12, with autonomy and responsibility gradually increasing to include multiple courses and independent teaching

Carnegie Mellon University, Department of Philosophy

Special Faculty | August 2019 – December 2020 | Pittsburgh

 Created syllabuses and delivered lectures for undergraduate courses covering topics at the intersection of philosophy & technology (AI, engineering ethics, etc.)

University of Sydney, Centre for Time

Postdoctoral Fellow | July 2011 - July 2013 | Sydney, Australia

 Coordinated weekly international guest speaker program while supervising graduate level dissertation project and instructing graduate seminars gbstrom@gmail.com +1-412-759-4591 Pittsburgh, PA, USA github.com/greg-strom linkedin.com/in/gbstrom greg-strom.github.io/portfolio/

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- MongoDB
- Node
- React
- React Native
- React Bootstrap
- · Configuring Heroku
- Amazon Web Services
- Angular
- Angular Material
- Git
- Responsive Design
- jQuery
- Test Driven Development

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

CareerFoundry - online May 2021 – March 2022

PhD in Philosophy

University of Pittsburgh August 2003 – August 2011

BA in Philosophy

University of Chicago September 1998 – June 2002

RESEARCH

'Deviant Causal Chains, Knowledge of Reasons, and *Akrasia*'

Published in *Topoi*, April 2014

'Multitasking, Consequentialism and Practical Imagination'

PhD Thesis University of Pittsburgh, 2011